Sagun Shrestha

 Sydney, Australia
 ■ sagun.shrestha10@gmail.com
 0484932738
 In LinkedIn
 Github

Profile

I am a seasoned Software Engineer with extensive experience in Python, PHP, SQL, and Linux. Additionally, I am also familiar with JavaScript and Go.

Skills

Python, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Flask, Django, JavaScript, Pandas, Backend, Linux, Scrapy, API Development, Data Science, Tailwind CSS

Experience

Software Developer, SQM Research

May 2022 - present | Sydney, Australia

- Implemented advanced stock recommendation tool for financial advisers.
- Built data pipelines to integrate multiple data sources along with tools for monitoring them.
- Developed custom APIs for clients which includes various government offices, banks and private institutes.
- Managed and improved legacy codebases written in PHP 5.6 and Python 2.7, streamlining processes to enhance overall efficiency and maintainability.
- Tech Stack: Python, PHP, MySQL, Linux, JavaScript

Software Developer, Get My Course

Jan 2018 - Feb 2022 | Freelance

- Created automated workflows saving hours of manual research tasks.
- Developed automated scripts for lead generation and data cleaning.
- Tech Stack: Python, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Selenium, Scrapy

Internship, YoungInnovations Pvt. Ltd.

Sep 2017 – Dec 2017 | Lalitpur, Nepal

- Developed news aggregator and traditional keyword based classifier
- Tech Stack: Python, Django, Scrapy, MySQL, JavaScript

Education

Masters of Data Science, Western Sydney University

Mar 2022 – Jan 2024 | Sydney, Australia

- 6.188/7 GPA (Distinction)
- Statistics, Predictive Analytics, Data Analytics, Machine Learning (PyTorch), Cloud Computing (AWS).

BSc (Computer Science), Tribhuvan University

Oct 2013 - Dec 2017 | Kathmandu, Nepal

- 75.43% (First Division)
- C, C++, Data Structure, Microprocessor, Cryptography, Database, Web Technologies, Computer Networks.

Projects

LLM for clinical notes, Researching application of LLM (GPT 3.5, LLAMA-2 70B) for analyzing clinical notes.

Eco Browse, Estimating carbon footprint of a webpage based on data usage and datacenter characteristics.

Entry Level Remote Job, Aggregates entry level remote jobs - https://entrylevelremotejob.com/

HN Deck, Tweetdeck like interface for browsing Hacker news - https://hndeck.sagunshrestha.com/

Others

- Won Intra college chess competition 2 times in a row.
- Published articles on Towards Data Science (a top data science publication)

 - Build your own dataset using Scrapy

 Ø